<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roxygen2 on Reproducible Random Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://yonicd.github.io/tags/roxygen2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Roxygen2 on Reproducible Random Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>yonicd@gmail.com (Jonathan Sidi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yonicd@gmail.com (Jonathan Sidi)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yonicd.github.io/tags/roxygen2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating roxygen2 package documentation</title>
      <link>https://yonicd.github.io/post/2017-09-18-sinew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yonicd@gmail.com (Jonathan Sidi)</author>
      <guid>https://yonicd.github.io/post/2017-09-18-sinew/</guid>
      <description>Thinking of creating a new package? Dread the task of function documentation? Afraid to run devtools::check(build_args = &#39;--as-cran&#39;) and get bombarded by Errors, Warnings, and Notes (oh my!) ? Wait&amp;hellip;. breathe!
After feeling all that anxiety and following all of Hadley&amp;rsquo;s directions online, I felt I was doing a lot of manual labour, and that a package should be doing all lot of this for me. So we wrote one - sinew (sin-yu).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sinew</title>
      <link>https://yonicd.github.io/post/2017-05-03-sinew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yonicd@gmail.com (Jonathan Sidi)</author>
      <guid>https://yonicd.github.io/post/2017-05-03-sinew/</guid>
      <description>Sinew is a R package that generates a Roxygen skeleton populated with information scraped from the function script.
Functionality  makeOxygen: Create skeleton for Roxygen2 documentation populated with information scraped from within the package function scripts. makeImport: Create import calls for DESCRIPTION, NAMESPACE and Roxygen2 makeDictionary: Create an R file of all the unique roxygen parameter fields in a package R subdirectory.  makeOxygen Function that returns the skeleton for roxygen2 documentation including title, description, return, import and other fields populated with information scraped from the function script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>